# **LEWIS SAUNDERS - ITV**

# **Frontend Engineer**

📞 07426774243 🏻 @ lewissaunders100@gmail.com 🔗 https://lewis-saunders-portfolio.vercel.app/ 👂 Farnborough, Hampshire

### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Front End Engineer with a strong proficiency in modern front end technologies and experience with back end technologies. Specialising in React, Next.js and TypeScript. Experienced with all Agile development methodologies such as Kanban, Scrum and Scrumban. Highly driven, motivated and quick to pick up new technologies, with a proven track record developing visible front-end services to strict deadlines.

## **SKILLS**

### Languages

JavaScript TypeScript HTML/CSS SQL PHP Ruby

#### Libraries/Frameworks/Other Technologies

React.js	Next.	js My	SQL Jes	t Sele	nium (	Capybar	a Cucum	ber Wo	rdpress	Tai	lwind
Laravel	Frame	er Motion	RESTf	ul APIs	GraphQL	. CMS	S UX/UI	Figma	MUI	Yup	Git
Jenkins	Jira	AWS	Docker	DevTools Po		stman SitePrism		BrowserStack		Tizen Studio	
Android S	Studio	XCode	Redis	Launch	Darkly	PNPM	Agile Dev	velopment	Scru	ım _	Kanban

Keycloak

# **STRENGTHS**



### **Self-Starter**

Consistency taking sole responsibility for tasks, bugs or potential UI improvements that I observe. I believe independent working is equally important as teamwork, and I pride myself on taking the incentive to take full ownership of my work



# **Supportive**

I ensure that my colleagues are aware of my willingness to assist them when they needed. Whether that be unblocking their technical barriers, or being an active listener. I believe supportive team work in this way leads to better results and a stronger team moral.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## 08/2024 - Present

London, United Kingdom

# Frontend Engineer

#### **Health Data Research UK**

- Development and maintenance of dynamic web applications using Next.js, Typescript and Material UI, ensuring high performance, SEO optimisation, meeting accessibility standards and matching UI/UX designs.
- Contributed approximately 50% to the development of our current project, which is a Next.js web-based application. This contribution includes key features, API routing, testing, auth integration and performance optimisations.
- Improved API efficiency by 20% by assisting backend developers in creating ~20 new routes.
- Implementation of backend functionality within these routes for database manipulation, altering data depending on the HTTP method passed through the route.
- Played a large part in the design of wireframes and mockups of our current project through Figma.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 06/2022 - Present

London

# Frontend Engineer

#### **ITV**

- Taking part in the development of responsive and user-friendly web applications, ensuring a seamless user experience across these different applications working on ITVX Browser, ITVX Connected TV & the ITV News website.
- Collaborating with UX/UI designers to translate design mockups and wireframes into quality code.
- Being a lead developer and primary driving force for multiple projects that are currently live on ITVX. These include the Regional News functionality which went live onto ITVX December 2023. And the news/sport short form & category page. This work can be seen on the ITVX app on both connected TV and browser.
- Frequently contributing & maintaining the ITV News website which is interacted with by thousands on a monthly basis.
- Being a significant part of the ITV Hub to ITVX rebrand from start to finish.
- Optimise website performance through code and asset optimisation.

#### 10/2020 - 06/2022

London

# Software Development Engineer in Test

#### **ITV**

- Oversee the QA process for Account Management on the ITV Hub.
- Solely recreating an entire codebase, which contained all acceptance tests for video related
  features on the ITV Hub, from the ground up. This was due to the old codebase being very
  outdated. This codebase is now used on the daily by the video team to ensure all video related
  functionality works as expected.
- Contributing to, and maintaining, automated testing frameworks for ITV web & mobile applications, ensuring comprehensive coverage of functional and non-functional requirements.
- Develop and maintain automated test scripts using industry-standard tools and frameworks.
- Participate in code reviews, conduct root cause analysis for defects, and work collaboratively with developers to resolve issues and improve overall product quality.

#### 09/2019 - 10/2020

London

05/2017 - 08/2018

Bracknell, Berkshire

07/2016 - 03/2017

Camberley, Surrey

10/2016 - 12/2016

Staines, Surrey

09/2015 - 01/2016

Birmingham

Technology Graduate

**ITV** 

Data Analyst

**IRi Worldwide** 

Assistant Manager & Pharmacy Advisor

**Boots UK** 

Entertainments Performer

**Merlin Entertainments** 

Bartender

**The Green Man** 

# **EDUCATION**

01/2018 - 01/2019

Kent

MSc Computer Science

**University of Kent** 

01/2012 - 01/2016

Birmingham

B.Sc. Biological Sciences with a Year in Computer Science University of Birmingham

01/2005 - 01/2012

Camberley, Surrey

A-Levels - Maths (A\*) Biology (A) Physics (A) Computing (A) GCSFs - 10 A\*s - Bs

**Collingwood College**